Preliminary Guide to the Marian King Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Marian King papers
1935-1973
MS 211
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
6
(6 boxes)
The papers consist of correspondence, writings, research material, photographs, and other papers relating to King's books. Much of the correspondence consists of letters from celebrities acknowledging receipt of copies of her books. Among the research material is a substantial amount relating to the White House Conference on Children (1970). The major portion of the papers consists of drafts, galley proofs, photographs, and other materials connected with the publication of her books.
King, Marian
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Marian King, 1955-1973.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The Marian King Papers is an unprocessed collection of autograph letters, correspondence, printed matter, typescripts, manuscripts, research materials, photographs, and other papers pertaining to the author Marian King and to her various children's books. The materials have been roughly grouped by type but are otherwise completely unorganized.
Approximately one-quarter of the collection consists of correspondence. Included here are autograph letters from politicians, authors, actors, and other celebrities, for the most part acknowledgments of free copies of King's books, and in some cases signed by secretaries. A partial list of names is appended to this inventory. There is also general correspondence concerning King's writings and research, and her participation in the 1970 White House Conference on Children. There are also greeting cards and printed invitations. Other printed matter and photographs are also mixed in with the correspondence, while further correspondence is probably mixed in with the research materials and printed matter.
Another quarter of the collection consists of printed matter. There is a substantial amount dealing with the White House Conference on Children; there are also copies of four of King's books ( What Would You Do?, 1962; A Gallery of Children, 1967; Mico and Piccolino, 1972; The Star of Bethlehem, 1968) and autographed copies of other authors' books. There are also pamphlets and leaflets on such topics as Mary Baker Eddy, Abraham Lincoln, and the John F. Kennedy Memorial, and newspaper clippings about King and her books. There is also a commonplace book containing both printed matter and manuscript notes about Ireland.
The final half of the collection is made up of manuscripts, typescripts, and galley proofs of a number of King's works, accompanied by notes, research materials, photographs used for illustrations, and related materials.
These papers have been given to Yale University by Marian King in a series of over eighty separate gifts since 1955.
Biographical / Historical
Marian King, author, studied abroad and began writing children's books in 1928. From 1940-1945, she served with the British Supply Missions in Washington, D.C.
Other Finding Aids
For a partial index of correspondents with Marian King, consult the Correspondents Index.
Children; Children's literature; Autographs; Authors; Women authors; King, Marian
- Inventory
  - Autobiographical sketch, [ca. 1960] (Box 1)
  - Autograph letters and general correspondence, Circa 1935-1973 (Box 1)
  - Autograph letters and general correspondence, Circa 1935-1973 (Box 2)
  - White House Conference on Children: printed matter and memorabilia, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Printed matter, undated (Box 2)
  - Newspaper clippings, Circa 1935-1973 (Box 2)
  - Printed matter, Circa 1937-1973 (Box 3)
  - Commonplace book re: Ireland, undated (Box 3)
  - Typescripts, manuscripts, galley proofs, notes, photographs, and other research materials for writings, Circa 1935-1973 (Box 4)
  - Typescripts, manuscripts, galley proofs, notes, photographs, and other research materials for writings, Circa 1935-1973 (Box 5)
  - Typescripts, manuscripts, galley proofs, notes, photographs, and other research materials for writings, Circa 1935-1973 (Box 6)